<DOC ID="CNA_ENG_19970930.0007" TYPE="story"><HEADLINE>GERMAN PARLIAMENTARIAN SAYS BEIJING SHOULD RENOUNCE USE OF FORCE</HEADLINE><DATELINE>Bonn,  Sept.  30  (CNA)(By Lillian Lin)</DATELINE><TEXT><P>Burkhard Hirsch, deputy speaker of theGerman Parliament, said Monday that the West should made it clear tomainland China that any attempt to solve the Taiwan issue with forcewould be unacceptable.</P><P>Hirsch made his point in a speech delivered at a receptionmarking the 40th anniversary of the founding of the German-ChineseSociety in Bonn. He emphasized that as a member of the United NationsSecurity Council, mainland China is obliged to adhere to theprinciple of not using force.</P><P>He noted that Germans experienced years of separation butreunited without force.</P><P>While some politicians believe the "one country, two systems"formula Beijing applies in Hong Kong could also be applied to Taiwan,Hirsch disagreed, pointing out that Hong Kong, unlike the Republic ofChina on Taiwan, was a ceded territory of the Chinese mainland.</P><P>He did, however, maintain that both sides of the Taiwan Straitare parts of a separated China.</P><P>He said that Taiwan and Germany are important to each other. TheGerman-Chinese Society has contributed to the promotion of political,economic and cultural contacts between Germany and Taiwan.</P><P>The German-Chinese Society was founded in February 1957. Thesociety's president, former German parliamentarian Ortwin Lowack,said at the reception Monday that the organization serves as animportant channel of communication between Germans and the people onTaiwan.</P><P>ROC Representative to Germany Charles King said that theGerman-Chinese Society has persistently provided advice to andsupport for the Republic of China.</P><P>Wolfgang Behrendt, vice chairman of the Bonn-TaipeiParliamentarian Group, was also invited to speak on the occasion. Helauded the achievements of the German-Chinese Society in promotingmutual understanding. He pointed out the efforts of the societycontributed to the realization of direct flights between Germany andTaiwan, simplification of visa applications, regular meetings betweenthe economic ministers of the two countries and elevation of thestatus of the ROC's representation in Germany.</P><P>More than 200 members and guests attended the celebrations, whichfeatured also Chinese and German music and poems by Yu Kuang-chung.</P></TEXT></DOC>
<DOC ID="CNA_ENG_19970930.0008" TYPE="story"><HEADLINE>CANADA HOSTING ASIA CONNECTS VIRTUAL CONFERENCE</HEADLINE><DATELINE>Ottawa, Sept. 29 (CNA)(By S.C. Chang)</DATELINE><TEXT><P>More than 600 youth from across Canada andaround the world began gathering Monday to officially open AsiaConnects, a conference organized by youth to celebrate Canada's Yearof the Asia-Pacific Region.</P><P>The youth will be meeting both physically and virtually untilOctober 5 to discuss issues related to the Asia-Pacific region.</P><P>Some 200 youth stationed in Winnipeg are joined by another 400 innine connected provincial and three international sites.</P><P>For many young people, it is their first chance to leave atextbook behind and learn about the world firsthand from each other.</P><P>Youth from Thailand, Singapore, Malaysia, Japan, the Philippinesand Cambodia will be meeting with their Canadian peers to discuss howCanada and Asian countries can work together to share their futuresin the global community.</P><P>Canadian Minister of Foreign Affairs Lloyd Axworthy and hisMalaysian counterpart, Abdullah Badawi, will speak to the delegateson Oct. 4 at all the sites through executive videoconferencing.Badawi is currently in Winnipeg leading a Malaysian delegation.Raymond Chan, Canada's secretary of state for Asia-Pacific, willspeak from the Vancouver site.</P></TEXT></DOC>
<DOC ID="CNA_ENG_19970930.0009" TYPE="story"><HEADLINE>SHARE PRICES PLUNGE 120.55 ON TAIEX</HEADLINE><DATELINE>Taipei,  Sept. 30 (CNA)(By Lin Wen-fen)</DATELINE><TEXT><P>Share prices stumbled on the Taiwan StockExchange Tuesday, with the weighted index, the market's keybarometer, dropping 120.55 points to finish at 8708.83.</P><P>The bourse opened at 8806.84 and experienced a high of 8812.01and a low of 8658.06.</P><P>Losers outnumbered gainers 298 to 109, with 66 remainingunchanged. In all, 1.38 billion shares changed hands on a marketturnover of NT$86.865 billion (US$3.047 billion).</P><P>Electrical engineering fell the most at 2.4 percent, followed byconstruction and finance issues at 1.0 percent, plastic and chemicalstocks at 0.9 percent and food stuff shares at 0.4 percent. Textileissues dropped 0.2 percent, while cement shares edged down 0.1percent.</P><P>Paper-making shares, the only category that gained momentum,edged up 0.1 percent.</P></TEXT></DOC>
<DOC ID="CNA_ENG_19970930.0010" TYPE="story"><HEADLINE>CONFERENCE ON EAST ASIA TO OPEN IN NEW YORK</HEADLINE><DATELINE>New York, Sept. 29 (CNA)(By David Wang)</DATELINE><TEXT><P>Catholic St. John's University will holdits 15th International Conference on Asian Affairs, titled "East AsiaToward the Twenty-first Century and Beyond," Oct. 4-5 on its New Yorkcampus.</P><P>Prominent American legislators and American and Chinese-Americanscholars have been invited to participate, said Dr. Cecilia Chang,St. John's vice president for International Relations and dean of itsCenter for Asian Studies, the host of the two-day conference.</P><P>The annual conference will examine the great political, economic,and social transformations in East Asia, with emphasis on Taiwan,Korea, Hong Kong and mainland China.</P><P>US Senator Daniel R. Coats, Congressman Matt Salmon andCongressman Curt Weldon are scheduled to attend the Oct. 4luncheon/lecture as keynote speakers, Chang said Monday.</P><P>The conference will include sessions on Japan and Korea, Taiwan,mainland China, Hong Kong and Taipei-Hong Kong-Beijing triangularrelations.</P></TEXT></DOC>
<DOC ID="CNA_ENG_19970930.0011" TYPE="story"><HEADLINE>HONG KONG EXODUS WORRIES VANCOUVER</HEADLINE><DATELINE>Ottawa,  Sept.  29  (CNA)(By S.C. Chang)</DATELINE><TEXT><P>The big fear in Vancouver these days isthey're going back -- those Hong Kong big-money investors who havebeen immigrating to British Columbia (B.C.), Canada, and who, withtheir wads of cash and trans-Pacific connections, were supposed toturn this laid-back city into some kind of frantic New York West.</P><P>The Toronto Star reported Monday that every few days, there isanother story in the Vancouver press testifying to this worryingphenomenon. Only 23 homes sold for more than C$1 million (US$725,000)in Greater Vancouver this year, one newspaper reported ominously.Another report noted that the average price for a home on the city'swest side, the area favored by wealthy Chinese immigrants, has fallenby C$250,000 (US$181,000), or 27 percent.</P><P>"The Chinese are going back to Hong Kong," one real estate agentwas quoted as explaining. And the province is spooked -- to such anextent that Premier Glen Clark's New Democratic Party (NDP)government is quietly asking Ottawa to back off from plans to maketax evasion by the rich more difficult, according to theVancouver-datelined story.</P><P>It was referring to a law requiring wealthy Canadian residents todisclose all worldwide assets worth more than C$100,000. In BritishColumbia, the law is a "cause celebre": From the Vancouver Board ofTrade to the NDP, the asset disclosure law is blamed for the exodusof rich Hong Kong immigrants.</P><P>"If you don't want the rich, you'll get more refugees andfamily-class immigrants," developer David Choi, son of Hong Kongmultimillionaire C.K. Choi, warned in the Vancouver Sun newspaper.</P><P>"The Chinese are very private about their money," Jenny Kwan, a31-year-old NDP member of the B.C. legislature, told The Star. "This(disclosure) law goes against our culture."</P><P>"I don't support tax evasion and never will," Clark said in aninterview. "But the question is: Is this the only way to deal withthe problem? Let's make sure this cure for tax evasion is the rightone and doesn't discourage the kind of investment we want."</P><P>The reason for the premier's concern is that immigration has beenbig business for British Columbia. Since the groundbreaking agreementbetween Britain and mainland China in 1984 to return Hong Kong toBeijing's rule at midnight June 30, 1997, Canada has been workinghard to woo the territory's wealthiest inhabitants.</P><P>In 1986, two new categories of landed immigrant were invented toattract the moneyed. A so-called entrepreneurial immigrant could wina place in Canada by promising to create at least one job. And a richperson with C$350,000 to invest (or in some cases C$250,000) couldqualify as an investor immigrant.</P><P>After three years, if these business immigrants met all the othercriteria, they were granted citizenship.</P><P>The programs have attracted well-to-do immigrants from Hong Kong,Taiwan and, more recently, mainland China. While many went to theToronto area, the largest concentration of business immigrantssettled in Vancouver.</P><P>David Ley, director of the University of British Columbia'sCenter of Excellence for the Study of Immigration and Integration,estimates that since 1990, about 50,000 business immigrants from HongKong have settled in Greater Vancouver.</P><P>They, and the money they brought with them, buffered B.C. fromthe recession of the '90s. Vancouver in particular prospered, as thenewcomers -- seemingly impervious to high housing prices -- bid upthe city's already overheated housing market.</P><P>There was some grumbling as the city absorbed thousands of newAsian immigrants, but in the main, British Columbians welcomed themoney. They didn't want it to stop, the Star said.</P><P>In fact, the vast majority of people from Hong Kong who came toCanada were not rich. As Kwan points out, most were like her parents:they settled, found work and set about making a life in a new place.</P><P>Immigration from Hong Kong peaked in 1994 as those planning toleave hurried to get out before the handover to mainland China. Thatyear, 10,296 business immigrants and their families settled inBritish Columbia. By last year, that number had dropped to 7,058.</P><P>But many of these wealthier investor immigrants had options notopen to their compatriots. As Gabriel Yiu, a 35-year-old broadcasterand small-business owner notes, for some immigrants a Canadianpassport was simply a form of insurance.</P><P>"In the Chinese community, we understand the problems," said Yiu,who immigrated from Hong Kong six years ago. "We have no harshfeeling toward those who leave. But we also hear of cases where thehusband makes plenty of money in Hong Kong and pays no Canadiantaxes, yet his family lives here."</P></TEXT></DOC>
<DOC ID="CNA_ENG_19970930.0012" TYPE="story"><HEADLINE>CITY, COUNTY ELECTIONS SET FOR NOV. 29</HEADLINE><DATELINE>Taipei  Sept. 30 (CNA)(By Lawrence Chu)</DATELINE><TEXT><P>Taiwan's Central Election Commission (CEC)on Monday officially announced that the year-end city and countyelections will be held Nov. 29.</P><P>The elections will determine the heads of 23 local governments,including those of all 16 counties on Taiwan, five municipal regionsand Fukien Province's two counties -- the outlying islands of Kinmenand Matsu.</P><P>CEC officials also announced candidates must register Oct. 26-30and that the official campaign period will be Nov. 19-28.</P><P>Taiwan's three major political parties -- the ruling Kuomintang,the Democratic Progressive Party (DPP) and the New Party -- are alleyeing the races with a great deal of interest.</P><P>KMT sources said the party is cautiously optimistic of victory.High ranking KMT officials assured voters that all the party'scandidates will be capable and morally impeccable, adding that theyshould have no problem winning the support of voters in their areas.</P><P>The DPP, the largest opposition party, has announced a plan tobegin campaigning for its candidates around the island on Oct. 2.</P><P>The DPP will make use of rock bands and several well-knownpoliticians at its rallies to boost support for its candidates.</P><P>According to observers, the opposition New Party is not expectedto do well in the local elections. A leading New Party figure,however, said the party plans to run candidates in Taipei County,Miaoli County, Taichung City, Nantou County, Kinmen County andLienchiang County (Matsu), and is looking to win all of those races.</P></TEXT></DOC>
<DOC ID="CNA_ENG_19970930.0013" TYPE="story"><HEADLINE>RESUMPTION OF ROC-KOREA AIR LINKS DEPENDS ON SEOUL'S ATTITUDE: SIEW</HEADLINE><DATELINE>Taipei, Sept. 30 (CNA)(By Lin Wen-fen)</DATELINE><TEXT><P>Premier Vincent Siew said Tuesday that theresumption of air links between Taiwan and South Korea lies in SouthKorean authorities showing goodwill and sincerity.</P><P>"The aviation accord talks between the Republic of China andSouth Korea have lasted for years," Siew said in response tointerpellation from legislator Chuang Chin-sheng of the rulingKuomintang that the lack of direct air links between Taiwan and SouthKorea following the severing of diplomatic ties in August 1992 hasgreatly inconvenienced people in both countries.</P><P>"Technically, there wouldn't be much difficulty in resuming theair links," Siew noted. "But regretfully, whenever it comes to thesubstantive part of the negotiations, South Korea has failed to showgoodwill and respect for the ROC's sovereignty," he said.</P><P>Asked how the two sides could eliminate the obstacles and reachan aviation accord, Siew declared, "South Korea has to change itsposition."</P><P>The premier said that although Taiwan handles its aviationrelations with other countries practically, it is totallyunacceptable for the countries concerned to show little respect forthe ROC's sovereignty.</P></TEXT></DOC>
