<DOC id="LTW_ENG_20081201.0001" type="story"><HEADLINE>Road Map in Iraq: When Mr. Obama Takes Office, a Sovereign Iraqi Government and a U.S. Withdrawal Timetable Will Be in Place</HEADLINE><TEXT><P>The following editorial appeared in Sunday's Washington Post:</P><P>Barack Obama recently reiterated his campaign promise to order up aplan for the withdrawal of U.S. forces from Iraq. But the Iraqi parliamenthas beaten him to it. Its ratification Thursday of a new bilateral militaryagreement with the United States not only establishes a timetable for theredeployment of American troops but delimits the missions they can undertakebetween now and the end of 2011. Mr. Obama has always said that his strategywas aimed at forcing Iraqi leaders to take responsibility for their countryand its security. In adopting and ratifying the accord, the government andparliament have taken a major step toward that goal.</P><P>By now Mr. Obama and most other opponents of the military surge launchedby President Bush nearly two years ago have acknowledged its success ingreatly reducing violence around Iraq. The completion of the Status ofForces Agreement and the accompanying strategic partnership accord with theUnited States shows how far the political system also has come. Two yearsago, Mr. Bush's national security adviser wrote a memo questioning whetherPrime Minister Nouri al-Maliki was able or even willing to assert hisauthority. But Mr. Maliki has been both skillful and forceful in extractingconcessions from the Bush administration -- such as the 2011 withdrawal date-- and winning agreement from Sunni as well as Shiite and Kurdishlegislators.</P><P>That those politicians were willing to publicly support three more yearsof American troops in Iraq just weeks before a hotly contested provincialelection was another sign that the new democratic system is gaining itsfooting. Legislators gave themselves an out by requiring a nationalreferendum next year that could allow Iraqi voters to advance the Americanwithdrawal date by a year. But that flinch is less significant than thewillingness of the government and parliament to stand up to pressure fromIran, which lobbied heavily against the Iraqi-U.S. accord, as well as to thedomestic opposition of the Sadr movement.</P><P>The Bush administration worked patiently and tirelessly to negotiate thenew agreement, which will have the effect of removing Iraq from UnitedNations supervision on Jan. 1. Having all but destroyed his presidencythrough mismanagement of the war, Mr. Bush can now fairly argue as he leavesoffice that his successor will inherit an Iraqi mission that has beenstabilized both militarily and politically. That's not the same thing as the"victory" Mr. Bush has often spoken of; Iraq could still unravel if itsleaders or the Obama administration act unwisely. There is now, however, aworkable road map for winding down the U.S. troop presence in the countryand for consolidating the new political system. Mr. Obama will receive thisframework from the president and the Iraqi government he has spent the lasttwo years campaigning against. Though we don't expect him to say so, Mr.Obama is fortunate that he was wrong, both about the surge and about thecapacity of Iraq's leaders.</P></TEXT></DOC>
<DOC id="LTW_ENG_20081201.0002" type="story"><HEADLINE>Preemptive Pardons: Mr. Bush Should Resist Any Temptation to Clear Officials Who Devised His Anti-Terrorism Strategy</HEADLINE><TEXT><P>The following editorial appeared in Sunday's Washington Post:</P><P>Some lawmakers and liberal interest groups have begun calling forcriminal investigations of Bush administration personnel who crafted orimplemented controversial anti-terrorism policies. As a result, PresidentBush may be contemplating preemptive pardons, including those involving CIAagents and others who carried out "extraordinary renditions" or "enhancedinterrogations." There are compelling reasons for the president not to godown that road.</P><P>The Bush administration distorted statutes and case law to legallyjustify interrogation techniques that had long been considered torture underdomestic and international law. It relied on sloppy or aggressive legalanalysis as a basis for evading judicial review of a warrantless wiretappingprogram. It has at every turn chosen the most expansive interpretation ofthe law to rationalize indefinite detentions and deny federal court reviewto those in custody. It has, in short, determined its preferred course ofaction first and then stitched together absurd readings of the law to defendthose choices.</P><P>The proper response to this will be for the next administration andCongress to determine, and it won't be an easy call. We're mindful of thedangers of excessive investigation. These decisions were made by anadministration on a war footing, in an effort to protect the country againstan unconventional enemy. In many cases Congress gave its active or tacitconsent. It could set a harmful precedent and possibly chill advice tofuture presidents if people are subjected to criminal prosecution foroffering unwise counsel.</P><P>At the same time, no country should be in the business of concealing itshistory. Shameful acts took place, and far from everything is known aboutthem. To this day, the trail of decision-making from top Pentagon officialsto Abu Ghraib perpetrators remains obscured. A bipartisan committee, modeledafter the Sept. 11 commission, might obtain definitive answers on how andwhy anti-terrorism decisions were made and executed and by whom. Such aninquiry could answer critical questions about the past, identify anyone whoshould be held accountable and help future administrations find a betterbalance.</P><P>The one sure thing is that a blanket pardon from Mr. Bush, even if hehas the legal right to issue one, would be wrong. It could make legitimateinquiries more difficult, while inflaming partisan outrage and suspicion.President-elect Barack Obama soon will inherit the power of the pardon. Ifthere are line officers who deserve such protection down the road, Mr. Obamawill have time enough to make a fair and just decision.</P></TEXT></DOC>
